S. Lane Faison papers, 1922-1981, bulk 1950-1976
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1923-1981; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 3, 7
  - Research Files, 1923-1978; 4.3; Archival Resource Key
    Faison's research files cover a variety of subjects. Most of the folders are related to art, but there are also folders on automobiles, housing, advertising, and many other topics. The files contain clippings, pamphlets, articles, and a few photographs.
    - Advertising, 1938-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 6.
    - American Sculpture, 1923-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 7.
    - Automobiles, circa 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Baroque, 1938-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 8.
    - English Painting, 1936-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Forgeries, 1924-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - French Painting, 1962-1977; 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - German and French Sculpture, 1936-1948; 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - H.H. Richardson Architecture in U.S.A., circa 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Housing, 1939-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 9.
    - Industrial Art, 1936-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Movies, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Poster Designs, 1942; 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Spanish Paintings, 1937; 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - U.S.A. 19th Century Painting, 1935-1947; 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - U.S.A. 20th Century Architecture, 1971; circa 1931-circa 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
      Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 10.
    - Urban Planning, 1940; 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 11.
    - Oversized Advertisements from Magazines from Box 3, Folder 30, 1938-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Oversized News Clippings and Images from Box 3, Folder 31, 1923-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Oversized News Clippings from Box 3, Folder 33, 1938-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Oversized News Clippings from Box 3, Folder 39, 1939-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Oversized News Clippings from Box 3, Folder 45, circa 1931-circa 1953; 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Oversized News Clippings from Box 3, Folder 46, 1940; 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Artists Files, 1922-1976; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Box 3-5, 7
  Artists reference files contain images of art, news clippings, articles and other assorted materials Faison collected for teaching and research.
  - Archipenko, Alexandre, circa 1940-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Arp, Jean, 1934-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Barnard, George Grey, 1938; 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Barye, circa 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Blake, William, 1934-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bonington, Richard Parkes, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Boudin, Eugene, 1933; 1972; 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bourdelle, Emile Antoine, 1931-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Brancusi, Constantin, 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Butler, Reg, 1957; 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1952-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 12.
  - Callery, Mary, 1950; 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Canova, Antonio, 1940-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Carpeaux, Jean Baptiste, circa 1958-circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 13.
  - Cassatt, Mary, circa 1940-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cezanne, Paul, 1920-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 14.
  - Constable, John, 1936-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Corot, J.B.C., circa 1930-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Couture, Thomas, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Daumier, Honore Victorin, 1951-1970; 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - David, Jacques Louis, 1971; circa 1930-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Davidson, Jo, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Degas, Edgar, 1934-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Delacroix, Eugene, 1930-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Despiau, Charles, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Dispirito, Henry, circa 1940-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Eakins, Thomas, circa 1931-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Ensor, James, circa 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Epstein, Jacob, circa 1938-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Forain, Jean Louis, circa 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Gauguin, Paul, 1933-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Gavarini, Paul, 1949-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Gericault, Theodore, 1934-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Giacometti, Alberto, 1955-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Gill, Eric, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Greenbaum, Dorothea, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Gros, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Guys, Constantin, circa 1950-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Harnett, William, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Horwitt, Will, circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Houdon, Jean-Antoine, 1938-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 15.
  - Ingres, Jean Auguste Dominique, circa 1950-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 16.
  - Jongkind, Johann B., circa 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - de La Tour, M. Quentin, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Lachaise, Gaston, circa 1964-circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Lassaw, Ibram, 1954; 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Laurens, Henri, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Lawrence, Thomas, circa 1940-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Lawrie, Lee, circa 1932-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Le Nain, circa 1940-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Liberman, Alexander, circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Lipton, Seymour, circa 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Macmonnies, Frederick, circa 1922-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Maillol, Aristide, circa 1971; 1929-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Manet, Edouard, 1972; 1949-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Manship, Paul, circa 1937; circa 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Marini, Marino, 1950; 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Mestrovic, Ivan, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Milles, Carl, 1936-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 56)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 17.
  - Millet, J.F., circa 1913; circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Monet, Claude, 1949-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Moore, Henry, 1940-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 59)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 18.
  - Morisot, Berthe, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Munch, Edvard, 1950-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Pissarro, Lucien, 1964-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Prud'Hon, circa 1940-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Puvis De Chavannes, Pierre, circa 1940-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Redon, Odillon, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Renoir, Pierre Auguste, 1929-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 19.
  - Rodin, Auguste, circa 1955-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rousseau, Henri, 1945-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rousseau, Theodore, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sargent, John Singer, circa 1938-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Seurat, Georges, circa 1957-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sisley, Alfred, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Signac, Paul, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Toulouse-Lautrec, 1938-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 20.
  - Turner, J.M.W., circa 1950-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Van Gogh, Vincent, circa 1935-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 21.
  - Whistler, James Abbott McNeill, circa 1933-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Zorach, William, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 7, 1952-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalog from Box 4, Folder 10, circa 1958-circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 12, 1920-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 37, 1938-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 38, circa 1950-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 56, 1936-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalogues from Box 4, Folder 59, 1940-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Oversized Article from Box 5, Folder 1, 1929-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Oversized Articles from Box 5, Folder 10, 1938-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Oversized Magazine and Articles from Box 5, Folder 12, circa 1935-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Printed Materials, circa 1935-1980; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 6, 7
  Printed materials consist of exhibition catalogs, bulletins, reports, news clippings, press releases, magazines and other miscellaneous printed matter.
  There is a copy of the Report on the Committee on the Visual Arts at Harvard University which examined the role of the arts in the curriculum. The report was by the Harvard Committee, whose chair was philanthropist and later Smithsonian regent John Nicholas Brown and the executive secretary was Faison. During World War II, President Roosevelt appointed Brown to General Eisenhower's staff as Special Cultural Advisor and the civilian head of the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section. Brown also argued against the removal of German-owned artworks to the United States in 1945.
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1937; 1955-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Williams College, 1954-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Museum Bulletins, 1966-1974; 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Williams College Bulletins, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Modern Art Annual Report, 1939-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Committee on the Visual Arts at Harvard University, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings: World War II, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 22.
  - News Clippings written by Faison, 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - News Clippings, 1956-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 23.
  - Press Releases, 1959-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Williams College Alumni Review Magazine, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1937-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Undated Miscellaneous, circa 1935-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 6, Folder 7, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 6, Folder 9, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)